PROFESSOR: So, let's talk
about its properties.
What does it expand?
It expands the top node, and the next b
on the next layer, and then the next
b squared on the second layer below
that, and so on until you hit a layer
that has a solution.
And then you'll hit the first
of those solutions you find.
So we process all nodes above
the shallowest solution.
How many are there?
That's going to tell us
the time complexity.
Still exponential, except now we
don't have to go all the way
down to depth m.
How deeply do we have to go?
Depends on how deep the solution is.
So let's let s be the
shallowest solution.
That means we're only going to process
these s tiers, and that means that the
time, the number of nodes we have to
expand is going to be b to the s.
So the search is going to take time.
It's still exponential, but now it's not
the depth of the entire tree, but
just the depth of the
shallowest solution.
How much space does our fringe
take in all of this?
Well, what's our fringe like?
What was it like when we
hit this solution?
Here what was on the fringe?
Well, in general we hadn't actually
done everything on that level.
And everything that we did do on that
level had children on the next level.
So you know, more or less the
fringe looks like the last
tier that we expanded.
Maybe kind of one tier below that.
So that's good, right?
It's not all the stuff above us.
So this thing's growing exponentially.
That's basically the whole graph
is on the last level, right?
And so the fringe is now
exponential as well.
That's a disadvantage to breadth-first
search is the fringe is very large,
and the advantage is because you're
being so thorough, you try all the
cheap stuff first, you're going to
find the shallowest solution.
Is this algorithm complete?
Well, you can do the first layer
and the second layer and so on.
Is it going to be complete?
Yeah.
So if a solution exists, it has
to exist at some finite level.
And you're only going
to go down that far.
Now, you could worry about cases like
what if the branching factor is
infinite, and so on, but with
appropriate, reasonable assumptions
here, yes, it will be finite because
you only have to go so deep.
And unlike leftmost prefixes so the
graph, which can be infinite, kind of
top prefixes of the graph are finite.
Is it optimal?
That's a little bit of an
ill-defined question.
Depends on the costs.
If the costs are general costs, right,
it could be that this solution is
actually cheaper than this one,
even though it's deeper.
So in general, no.
But if the costs are all one, then
yes, this will be optimal.